Word2vec is just one type of forward embedding.
Word2vec 是一种正向嵌入
Recently, several other related approaches have been proposed that are really promising.
最近有人提出几种非常有潜力的相关方法
GloVe or global vectors for word representation is one such approach that tries to
用于词表示法的 GloVe（全局向量）正是其中之一
directly optimize the vector representation of
它尝试利用同现统计法
each word just using co- occurrence statistics,
直接优化每个词的向量表示法
unlike word2vec which sets up an ancillary prediction task.
而 word2vec 进行的是辅助预测任务
First, the probably that word j appears in the context of word i is computed,
首先 对于指定语料库中的所有词对 ij
pj given i for all word pairs ij in a given corpus.
计算词 j 在词 i 的上下文中出现的概率 P(j | i)
What do we mean by j appears in context of i?
“j 在 i 的上下文中出现”是什么意思？
Simply that word j is present in the vicinity of word i,
意思是词 j 出现在词 i 附近
either right next to it,
与它相邻或者
or a few words away.
相隔几个词
We count all such occurrences of i and j in our text collection,
统计文本集中 i 和 j 出现这种情况的所有次数
and then normalize account to get a probability.
然后将计数标准化 获得概率
Then, a random vector is initialized for each word, actually two vectors.
然后 对每个词初始化一个随机向量 实际是两个向量
One for the word when it is acting as a context,
一个代表作为上下文的词
and one when it is acting as the target. So far, so good.
另一个代表作为目标的词 很好
Now, for any pair of words, ij,
现在 对于任何词对 ij
we want the dot product of their word vectors,
我们想让其词向量的点积
w_i times w_j, to be equal to their co-occurrence probability.
Wi 乘以 Wj 等于其同现概率
Using this as our goal and a suitable last function,
以此为目标 利用适当损失函数
we can iteratively optimize these word vectors.
可以通过迭代方式优化这些词向量
The result should be a set of vectors that capture
结果应为一组向量 这个向量捕捉了
the similarities and differences between individual words.
各个词之间的相似性和差异性
If you look at it from another point of view,
从另一个角度看
we are essentially factorizing
我们实质上是将
the co-occurrence probability matrix into two smaller matrices.
同现概率矩阵分解成两个小矩阵
This is the basic idea behind GloVe.
这是 GloVe 的基本概念
All that sounds good,
听起来很好
but why co-occurrence probabilities?
但是为什么使用同现概率？
Consider two context words,
假设有两个语境词
say ice and steam,
ice 和 steam
and two target words, solid and water.
以及两个目标词 solid 和 water
You would come across solid more often in the context of ice than steam, right?
相比 steam 来讲 在 ice 的上下文中 你更容易想到 solid 对吧？
But water could occur in either context with roughly equal probability.
但是 water 在两个上下文中出现的概率基本相等
At least, that's what we would expect.
至少我们是这样认为的
Surprise. That's exactly what co-occurrence probabilities reflect.
令人吃惊的是 这正是同现概率所反映的东西
Given a large corpus,
在较大语料库中
you'll find that the ratio of P solid given
你会发现 P(solid | ice)
ice to P solid given steam is much greater than one,
与 P(solid | steam) 的比远远大于 1
while the ratio of P water given ice and P water given steam is close to one.
而 P(water | ice) 与 P(water | steam) 的比接近 1
Thus, we see that co-occurrence probabilities
因此可以看出 同现概率
already exhibit some of the properties we want to capture.
已经表现出我们想要捕捉的某些特征
In fact, one refinement over using
实际上 相比使用原始概率值
raw probability values is to optimize for the ratio of probabilities.
一种改进方法是优化概率的比
Now, there are a lot of subtleties here,
这里有很多微妙之处
not the least of which is the fact that the co-occurence probability matrix is huge.
最明显的就是 同现概率矩阵是巨大的
At the same time,
同时
co-occurrence probability values are typically very low,
同现概率值一般非常低
so it makes sense to work with the log of these values.
因此可以对这些值的对数进行处理
I encourage you to read the original paper that introduced
我建议你阅读介绍 GloVe 的原论文
GloVe to get a better understanding of this technique.
以便更好理解这种技术